CHRIS ARSENAULT

🔾 www.chrisarsenault.dev 📞 647-920-0506

♥ Toronto Ontario

mvnameischrisa in chrisstanarsenault

n chrisstanarsenault

EDUCATION

SUMMARY

Lighthouse Labs Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Oct. 2018 to Jan. 2019

A full stack developer from Toronto, Ontario, with a passion for all things front-end. I am extremely motivated and driven to grow my knowledge and skills in web development. With my many years of working in the hospitality district, I have substantial experience of working as a team, as well as team building. I am excited to bring my eager attitude and past team experience into an innovative environment.

PROJECTS

https://github.com/chrisstanarsenault/drawango

A drawing/guessing party game built to learn to work further with React and Canvas in a realtime drawing environment.

TechStacks: React, CSS/SASS, Express, NodeJS, Websockets

JUNGLE APP

https://github.com/chrisstanarsenault/jungle-rails

An e-commerce Rails app built for learning Rails

TechStacks: Ruby, Rails, Bootstrap, CSS/SASS, PG, Active Record

CHATTY APP

https://aithub.com/chrisstangrsengult/chatty-app Simple single page chat app built with React and Websockets

TechStacks: React, CSS/SASS, Express, NodeJS, JS, Websockets

https://github.com/chrisstanarsenault/hookeai-poke

A food ordering and pickup service for the fictitious restaurant 'Hookeai Pookeai'

TechStacks: HTML, CSS/SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Express, NodeJS, EJS, PostSQL, Knex, AJAX, Twilio

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, Ruby

FRAMEWORKS, LIBRARIES, ENVIRONMENTS: NodeJS, React, AJAX, Express, Knex, JOuery, Bootstrap, Rails, Websockets/Socket,io, Vue

DATABASES, SYSTEMS, CMS: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Git, WordPress

EMPLOYMENT

416 MEDIA

WordPress Developer (freelance)

Toronto, Ontario Oct. 2019 to Oct. 2019

- data entry, migrating content from old client site to new updated site
- created basic html tables to help organize some of the information custom css work to fix with some of the formatting and aesthetic
- connected GoogleMap API and billing to new account

WORLD LEGAL SUMMIT

WordPress Developer

Toronto, ON Mar. 2019 to Current

- general maintenance of the pre-existing website
- customize layouts as per client's needs
- plugin maintenance which increased speed and search optimization. Brought PageSpeed score from initial 35% to 74% worked directly with each city host (approx 30-40) clients to add new updates and revisions to their individual event page (adding logos, documents, location details, speaker information, etc)
- implementing any new requested features or software needs such as:
 live streaming capabilities for each host location
- set up Zendesk and created a custom theme for a knowledge base and community section
- integrated a method to connect the Mailchimp account with separate GoogleSheets to collect signup information for each host, when interested parties requested an invite to their cities Summit.
- TORONTO LAWN TENNIS CLUB

Member Services Supervisor

Toronto, Ontario June 2013 to Oct. 2018

- booking tennis/squash courts for members - giving tours to new perspective members
- answering all inquiries
- being knowledgeable and up-to-date on all club related news and events
- training all new front desk staff
- assisting with any requests from other departments

AWARDS

Toronto Lawn Tennis Club, EMPLOYEE OF THE YEAR

2014

- I received this award for my dedication, focus, and willing to go above and beyond the call of duty

VOLUNTEERING

HEALTH & SAFETY COMMITTEE Co-Chair Toronto Lawn Tennis Club

2014 to 2018

- assisted the Chair run monthly committee meeting, and organize monthly club inspections

- organized MDS files and kept all MDS sheets up to date
- Attended classes to receive Health and Safety certification